Fairfield Families Collection Ms 37
Fairfield Museum and History Center
Fairfield Families Collection
1693-2004
Ms 37
Fairfield Museum and History Center
3.0 Linear feet (9 boxes, 2 oversize items)
various
Conditions Governing Access note
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Biographical/Historical note
Information for some families can be found in their section of the finding aid.
Scope and Contents note
This artificial collection contains small collections from families as well as individuals in Fairfield. They are arranged alphabetically in folders with later accruals in later boxes and not in alphabetical order. Consult the finding aid for the location of a particular family.
Adams family; Allen family; Alvord family; Angevine, Evelyn; Anti family; Arens, Egmont; Baldwin, Abraham D., 1788-1862; Barlow family; Barnum, P. T. (Phineas Taylor), 1810-1891; Beardsley, Clifford W., d. 1957; Benson family; Brett, George P. (George Platt), 1893-1984; Bridgeport Whaling Co. (Bridgeport, Conn.).; Budd, Burr; Budington family; Burr, Harriet E.; Busat, Victoria; Callender family; Callender, Esther Sayre, 1793-1855; Callender, Thomas L. (Thomas Loring); Chapman family; Chauncey family; Chauncey, Charles, 1747-1823; Chauncey, Israel; Child, Frank Samuel, 1854-1922; Clark family; Clark, Cameron, b. 1922; Coley family; Cook family; Corbusier, Alfred B. (Alfred Bascomb), b. 1823; Daily, Thomas A., b. 1956; Davis family; Denny family; Disbrow family; Donaldson, Chase; Donaldson, Elinor Thompson; Downs family; Dunning family; Eddy, George; Eliot, Andrew, 1744-1805; Fairchild family; Fairfield County Agricultural Society.; Fairfield Historical Society (Fairfield, Conn.).; Fairfield Memorial Library (Fairfield, Conn.).; Fitzgerald family; Flood Management Program (Conn.) .; Forgue family; Frank, John M.; Gallagher, William D., 1845-1884; Gilbert, Burr; Gilden, Joseph; Glover, Addie M.; Goodsell family; Gorham family; Gray family; Gray, Asahel Johnson, 1814-1908; Gray, John Silliman, b. 1845; Green family; Griffin, Betty; Halasz family; Halasz, Julius, d. 1952; Halasz, Mary Anti; Hall family; Harvest (Ship) .; Havard, Aline, 1889-; Hawkins family; Hazard family; Hazard, John, 1719-1771; Henshaw family; Holbrook family; Howell family; Hubbard family; Hubbell family; Jackson family; Johnson family; Judah, Moses; Judson family; Judson, David, 1747-1841; Kent family; Kent, Mary Hazard; Kent, Moss; Kruzsylak, William George; Lacey, Charlotte Alvord; Lewis family; Lockwood family; Lowery, Charles; Lowery, Sarah Jones, 1828-1911; Mallett family; McGarry, Patrick; Merchant, Joel; Merritt Parkway Advisory Committee.; Middlebrook family; Millbank family; Mills family; Morris, Annie M.; Nash family; Neale, Harold W.; Osgood, Samuel, 1812-1880; Parrack family; Penfield family; Pepper family; Pepper, Ellis S.; Pike family; Pike, Samuel, 1827-1890; Prentice, Winthrop; Raymond family; Redfield family; Riley family; Riley, George, ca. 1842-1867; Riley, Patrick, 1813-1892; Robenson, Eunice, 1790-1854; Rodgers, Richard, d. 1980; Rogers family; Rogers, Dorothy; Rowland, Joseph F.; Rumsey family; Scofield family; Sheffield, Paschal; Shelton family; Shelton, Philo, 1785-1825; Shelton, Sarah Bradley, 1818-1863; Shelton, William, 1798-1883; Sherman, David, 1665-1753; Sherwood, David H., 1829-1892; Sherwood, John Henry, 1825-1918; Smedley family; Smedley, John, 1734-1786; Smedley, Samuel, 1753-1812; Smith family; Smith, Adeline; Smith, Horace; Southport Congregational Church (Southport, CT).; Spencer, Robert; Squier family; Szymanski family; Taintor family; Taylor family; Taylor, Mary Darlington; Tomlinson, Gideon, 1740-1854; Tracy family; Treadwell family; Trubee, Ansel, 1747-1823; Upshaw, Willie, 1957-; Wales, Isabelle Guilbert; Webb, Joseph, 1666-1732; Welch, Elijah; Welles, Dot; Wilson family; Wilson, Eleazer, 1792-1857; Wilson, Thurza Nichols, 1826-1917; Winton, Joseph; Winton, Peter; Worden family; Worden, Nathaniel Sherwood, b. 1813; Worden, Oliver N., b. 1817; Wordin, Samuel, 1760-1833; Wordin, Thomas C., 1787-1852; Wordin, William, 1734-1808; Wordin, William, 1760-1814; Working Girl's Vacation Society..; Account books--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Agriculture--Connecticut.; Agriculture--New York (State); Agriculture--Societies, etc.; Authors, American--20th century.; Autograph albums.; Baseball players.; Baseball--Japan.; Bible records.; Bridgeport (Conn.); Business--United States.; Churches--Connecticut.; Connecticut. National Guard; Correspondence.; Deeds--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Diaries.; Diplomas.; Draft registration--Connecticut.; Fairfield (Conn.)--History; Fairfield (Conn.)--Social life and customs.; Fairfield (Conn.). Public Schools; Fairfield(Conn.); Farmers--Connecticut; Fish and game licenses--Connecticut.; Genealogy.; Green Cottage; Merchants--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Merritt Parkway (Conn.); Military orders; Municipal officials and employees.; Music Scores.; Oyster fisheries; Passports.; Patent licenses--United States.; Photographs.; Political campaigns--United States--Press coverage--United States.; Probate records--Connecticut--Fairfield; Real property--Valuation.; Receipts(financial records); Roads--Connecticut; Schools--Connecticut.; Sermons.; Ships; Slaves--Connecticut.; Southport(Conn.); Stratfield (Conn.); Stratford (Conn.); Wills.; Writs--Connecticut.
- Adams Family Papers, 1923-1962; Box I-Folder A; 41 items
  Scope and Contents note
  This collection consists of correspondence, deeds and mortgage papers concerning land and buildings at 1975 Mill Plain Road sold by Russell Lombard to Arthur and Frederick Adams who ran a wholesale florist business there. This property was sold to Joseph Neverdousky in 1960.
  General note
  These items are from accession number L87.June.2
- Allen Family Papers, 1772-1915; Box I-Folder A-I; 6 items
  - Deed from Ebenezer Jesup to Stephen Allen, 1813
  - Deed from Daniel Murray, Jr. to Benjamin Allen, 1814
  - Probate paper, estate distribution of David Allen, 1779
  - Mortgage release from Sereno Allen to Lizzie M. Thomas, et al., 1915
  - Bill from John Allen, Fairfield town treasurer, 1772
  - Bill from Gould Allen for gaol expenses, 1830
- Alvord Family Papers, 1774-1866; Box I-Folder B; 6 items
  - Writ, Belah Alvord vs. John Holland, 1774
  - Writ, John Alvord vs. Eliphelet Bradley, 1786
  - Writ, John Alvord vs. Joel Hubbill, 1791
  - Writ, John Alvord vs. Daniel Meeker, 1818
  - Letter, Jessup Alvord to Charles L. Mills, 1866
  - Letter, P. D. Carrique to E. J. Alvord (written on a Fairfield House (summer resort) brochure), 1866
- Angevine, Evelyn Papers--Merritt Parkway Advisory Committee Records, 1974-1977, 1986; Box VIII-Folder BB
  Biographical/Historical note
  These items from the estate of Evelyn Angeline were found among the records of the Sasquanaug Association and donated to the Historical Society by that organization since they did not directly document their own work. Angeline served on the Merritt Parkway Commission in the 1950's and continued her interest in the scenic roadway through preservation efforts in the 1970's and 1980's. The records Angevine saved are very scattered. This series comes from accession number L1998.20.
  - Flyer, memoranda, newspaper clipping, Folder BB
- Anti/Halasz Family Papers, 1904-1956; Box IX; 3 folders
  Julius Halasz immigrated to the United States from Hungary in 1906. He married Maria (Mary) Anti in 1912. Mary immigrated from Hungary in 1906 with her father Janos (John), mother Katalin (Katherine) Varga Anti and her brother Janos (John). The spelling of the Anti family name was later changed to Antey due to the negative connotation of Anti.
  Julius and Mary built a house at 82-84 Dalewood Avenue in the Grasmere area.
  Julius worked at Casco and kept a garden in a lot on Ardmore Street. He enjoyed making his own wine from the grapes he grew. He was killed by a car while crossing the street in 1952. He had just left the Ash Creek Saloon after having a night cap.
  All the family members are buried at Mountain Grove Cemetery.
  All biographical information is courtesy of the donor of the collection, Katherine E. Antey Philbrook whose grandparents were Janos (John) and Katherine.
  Related Archival Materials note
  The wax flower bridal headdress worn by Mary Anti Halasz at her wedding is in the museum collections.
  The items in this collection are from accession number L2006.12.
  - Folder L
    - Passports for Julius Halasz and James Anti (and family), ca. 1906
    - Ticket for Anti family members passage on the Bremen, 1906
    - Certificate of Naturalization for Julius Halasz, 1926
    - Alien registration cards for Mary Anti Halasz, 1955
    - Julius Halasz death certificate, 1952
  - Folder M
    - Savings account passbook, 1909-1925
    - Mortgage documents, 1932-1933
    - Building contract, 1932
    - Receipt, 1958
  - Folder N-Photographs
    - Tintype, Katherine, Mary and John Jr. Anti
    - Julius and Mary Halasz in wedding attire, 1912
    - Julius and Mary Halasz, 1921
    - Mary Anti, 1908
    - Julius and Mary Halasz, ca. 1915
    - Mary Anti, ca. 1921
    - Julius Halasz, ca. 1912
    - Julius Halasz, 1920
    - Julius and Mary Halasz, ca. 1915
    - Julius and Mary Halasz, ca. 1933
    - Home at 82-84 Dalewood Ave, 1930
    - Home at 82-84 Dalewood Ave, 2004
- Arens, Egmont Papers, Box VIII-Folder Y
  Mr. Egmont Arens, who owned waterfront property in Southport at 273 Harbor Rd., proposed the construction of a swimming pool and sea wall, and later a floating dock into the Mill River. His correspondents included the U.S. Engineer Office and the Connecticut Flood Control and Water Policy Commission. Plans were drawn by Andrew Huntington and Thomas Currie.
  - Correspondence, plot plans, blueprints, maps, and notes, 1939-1949
- Baldwin, Abraham D. Papers, 1863; Box II-Folder M; 1 item
  - Probate paper of Abraham Baldwin (1788-1862)
- Barlow Family Papers, 1748-1784; Box I-Folder C; 8 items
  - Deed from Samuel Trowbridge to John Barlow, 1748
  - Writ, William Seeley vs. David Barlow, 1748
  - Writ, Gershom Stephens vs. David Barlow, 1773
  - Writ, John Barlow vs. Richard Ellwood, 1774
  - Writ, David Hubbell vs. Nehemiah Barlow, 1784; 2 items
  - Writ, George Barlow vs. David Hubbell, 1784
  - Letter from Joel Barlow to Ezekial Williams
- Barnum, P. T. Papers, 1851-1890; Box I-Folder D; 22 items
  P. T. Barnum (1810-1891) was born in Bethel, CT. Although he is most famous for his circuses and museums, he was also a member of the Connecticut legislature, a bank president, Mayor of Bridgeport, a real estate dealer, newspaper editor and general entrepreneur. He settled in Bridgeport, CT in 1848 in an area which was at that time part of Fairfield.
  - Letter from Oliver H. Perry, 1877
  - Letter from Dr. Osgood, 1879; 2 items
  - Letter from Dr. L. C. Warner, 1880, 1883, 1890; 3 items
  - Letter from Mrs. Ethel Thomas, n.d.
  - Letter from Mr. Smith (photocopy), n.d.
  - Promissory note from Julia A. Denning to P. T. Barnum, 1886
  - Letter from Peter Barnum to Ezra (photocopy) with accompanying letter, 1845, 1981
  - Funeral service and commemoration of P. T. Barnum, 2 items
  - Etching of P. T. Barnum's house, n.d.
  - Jenny Lind programs, 1851, n.d.; 2 items
  - Tickets and programs, 4 items
  - Republican ticket, 1880
  - Deed from P. T. Barnum to Mrs. Marth G. Aumack, 1880
  - Broadside of the Emancipation from prison of P. T. Barnum, Danbury, CT, 1832; Oversize Item C
- Beardsley, Clifford W. Papers, 1917-1957; Box VII-Folder L
  - Warranty deeds concerning property on Jackson Ave. in Fairfield., 1917, 1922
  - Certificate of devise, 1957
- Benson Family Papers, 1814-1935; Box I-Folder E; 18 items
  - Bills and bills receipted to Abraham Benson, 1814-1815; 8 items
  - Bills and bills receipted from Abraham Benson, 1 item
  - Bills and bills receipted from William Benson, 1816, 1820; 2 items
  - Account, n.d.
  - Writ, David Rowel vs. Abraham Benson, 1821
  - Land maps and survey bill, 1821, n.d.; 3 items
  - Letter from Franklin D. Roosevelt to Mr. Hevlyn D. Benson (copy), 1931
  - Letter from Finette Benson Nichols to Mr. J. Walter Perry, 1935
- Brett, George Platt Sr. Papers, 1924-1936; Box V-Folders A-C
  George Platt Brett (1858-1936) was born in London. He became president of the Macmillan Publishing Co. in New York and moved to Greenfield Hill in Fairfield where he maintained an outstanding pinetum on Congress St.
  The items in this series come from accession number L88.Jan.2.
  - George Platt Brett Sr.'s diaries, 1924, 1927-1932; Folder A; 2 items
  - George Platt Brett Sr.'s diary, 1932-1936; Folder B
  - George Platt Brett's, Sr. obituary and newspaper article, 1936; Folder C
- Budd, Burr Papers, 1877; Box I-Folder F; 3 items
  - Application for patent for improvement in gun cleaning of Burr L. Budd
  - Patent reissue
  - Letter to Samuel Glover re: patent
- Budington Family Papers, 1777-1890; Box VIII-Folder B
  - Permit, issued to Walter Budington (copies), 1777-1778; 1 items
  - Receipt (copy, 1779
  - Birth, death and marriage records, 1809-1890; 2 items
  - Typed genealogy of Walter Budington, n.d.
- Burr, Harriet E. Papers, Box VIII-Folder W
  - Autograph album, 1879-1887; From internal evidence, the owner of the autograph album appears to be Harriet E. Burr, daughter of William Burr and Catherine Burr Sherwood. The signatures and poems in the album were inscribed by family members and friends, the majority of whom lived in Connecticut and New Jersey. Harriet also pasted in a signature of "Silus B. Sherwood, 1828", possibly taken from a letter.
- Busat, Victoria Papers, Box IX-Folder I
  Victoria and August Busat lived on Tunxis Hill in Fairfield in the 1940's.
  - Poem written in German, 1955
  - Fragment of a note
- Callender Family Papers, 1839-1949; Box I-Folder G; 42 items
  Thomas Loring Callender was married to Esther Sayre (1795-1855), daughter of James Sayre and Eunice Dennie. Her first husband was Moses Judah who died around 1830. Judah and Callender was a lock and hardware business in New York City.
  - Letters to Thomas Callender, business and personal, 1822-1847; 33 items
  - Letters to Mrs. Thomas Callender, New York City from Elizabeth Hull, Fairfield, CT are of local interest, 1839-1849; 9 items
- Chapman Family Papers, 1775-1819; Box I-Folder H; 11 items
  Daniel Chapman (1688/9-1741) married Grissel Dennie (1696/7-1754). Their son Dennie Chapman married Desire Lovel and they had sons Lovel Chapman, b. 1755, and Dennie Chapman, b. 1757.
  - Writ, Nathan Godfry vs. Dennie Chapman, 1775
  - Writ, Lovel Chapman vs. Alva Burr, 1803
  - Bills to Dennie Chapman, 1788, n.d.; 2 items
  - Deed from Samuel Gordon to Albert Chapman, 1819
  - Bond from Simon Couch to Lovel Chapman, 1795
  - Bond from Gershom Bulkley to Dennie Chapman, 1790
  - Due payment from Dennie Chapman, Jr., 1788
  - Promissory notes, 1785-1789; 3 items
- Chauncey Family Papers, 1714, 1847; Box IX-Folder A
  The Chauncey family was from Stratford, CT. Charles Chauncey was a minister and president of Harvard College.
  Custodial History note
  This series was a gift of Mr. and Mrs. C. H. R. Godfrey probably in the 1950's.
  - Copy of will, 1714
  - Copies of baptismal record and probate litigation for Israel Chauncey, 1847
  - Deposition, 1847
  - Copy of biographical entry from Elliot's Biographical Dictionary
  - Genealogical chart
- Child, Frank Samuel Papers, 1907-1922; Box I-Folder I; 9 items
  Frank Samuel Child (1854-1922) was minister of the First Church of Christ, Fairfield, CT from 1888 to 1920 and one of the founders of the Fairfield Historical Society in 1902.
  - Addresses, 1907, 1910; 2 items
  - Book advertisement for An Old New England Town
  - In Memoriam service, 1922
  - Memorial messages, n.d.; 2 items
  - Letters to the Rev. Frank S. Child from Timothy Dwight re: dedication of Fairfield Library, 15 April 1903, 22 July 1903; 2 items
  - Invitation to attend the groundbreaking of a statue of Joan of Arc, 1915
- Clark Family Papers, Box II-Folder N1 and N2
  Cameron Clark, Jr. attended Yale and upon graduation joined the Navy. He was assigned to the USS Prairie State and then to the sub chase training center in Miami, FL. In January 1945 he transferred to Newport, RI, assigned to the USS Parmina and saw the end of the War in Tokyo Harbor. He was mustered out of the service in 1946.
  The items in this series come from accession numbers L88.Jan.2 and L90.Jul.1.
  - Postcards to Cameron Clark (b. 1992) and his sister Cordelia Clark (b. 1925) from Ellsworth Merwin (1913-1946). These postcards were written on a western trip during July, August and September 1935., Folder N1
    Photocopies of the cards are on the library shelf, Clark-Merwin Postcard collection (808.86932 c592).
  - Naval papers of Ensign Cameron Clark, Jr., 1942-1946; Folder N-2
- Coley Family Papers, 1790-1855; Box I-Folder J; 6 items
  - Military letter to H. M. Coley from Horace Banks, 1836
  - Michael Coley's bills of sale of Sloop Nancy, 2 items
  - Petition of Levi Coley, 1842
  - To Hezekiah Coley, Justice of the Peace re: tenant removal, 1855
  - Writ, John Coley vs. Gersham Hubbell, 1790
- Corbusier, Alfred B. Papers, 1853-1890; Box IV-Folder L; 2 items
  John Peniston Corbusier, a furniture maker, was born in 1792 in Bermuda and died in Southport, CT in 1877. His son, Alfred Bascomb Corbusier, was born in New York City in 1823 and lived in Bridgeport, CT. He was a furniture varnisher and later a dancing instructor.
  - Alfred B. Corbusier account book, 1853-1890
    Gift of Mrs. Charles Hart Spencer, Jr.
  - Hand-book for the pupil of A. B. Corbusier, 1867
- Daily, Thomas A. Papers, 1980-1989; Box VI
  Thomas A. Daily was born in 1956 and ran as the Republican nominee for State Representative from the 134th District. He lost the election.
  Items in this series are from accession number L90.Dec.15.
  - Campaign leaflets, papers and buttons, 1980-1989; Folder A; 3 items
  - Newspaper clippings, 1980-1989; Folder B; 40 items
- Davis Family Papers, 1771-1838; Box I-Folder K; 11 items
  - Deed from Thomas Davis to Joseph W. Davis, 1814
  - Gere Davis bankruptcy petition, 1804
  - Writ, Ebenezer Davis vs. William Cable, 1771
  - Writ, John Crossman vs. John Davis, 1773, 1774; 3 items
  - Writ, Mary Davis vs. Medad Bradley, 1784; 3 items
  - Writ, Ebenezer Davis (Weston) vs. Tony Jacklin (Freeman), 1823
  - Letter re: Abigail Davis' husband's pension, 1838
- Denny (Dennie) Family Papers, 1709-1714; Box I-Folder L; 9 items
  James Dennie (1702/3-1759) son of Albert married Eunice Sturgis. Their daughter Eunice (1732-1805) married Thaddeus Burr (1735-1801), a leading citizen of Fairfield.
  - Albert Denny's estate expense account, 1709, 1710, n.d.; 3 items
  - Albert Denny's estate distribution, 1713, 1714
  - Papers re: Joseph Wakeman's guardianship of Albert Denny's children, 1709-1714; 6 items
- Disbrow Family Papers, 1772-1838; Box I-Folder M; 9 items
  - Deed from Joseph Gray to Isaac Disbrow, 1808
  - Deed from Aaron Rumsey (Westport) to Joseph Disbrow, 1838
  - Writ, Elias Disbrow vs. Joshua Disbrow, 1772
  - Writ, Comfort Sands vs. Jabez Disbrow, 1773
  - Writ, Nathan Disbrow vs. Ebenezer Squire, 1775
  - Writ, Ananias Langin vs. Joshua Disbrow, 1782
  - Writ, Asahel Disbrow vs. Elias Disbrow, 1789
  - Writ, Justus Disbrow vs. Stephen Guyer, 1792
  - Money receipt to Joseph Disbrow, 1797
- Donaldson, Chase Papers, Box IX; 2 folders
  Chase Donaldson was born in California to Dr. Frank Donaldson and Ethel Sprague. He was the great-grandson of Lincoln’s Secretary of the Treasury Salmon P. Chase. He married Elinor Thompson on 14 June 1930. He was previously widowed with three children. Elinor was born in Delaware and attended Miss Porter’s School in Farmington.
  After marrying the couple lived in the Oliver T. Sherwood house on Pequot Road (now number 683) from approximately 1933-1938. Chase also maintained a home in New York City where he worked as a broker.
  The items in this collection were found by the donor during a 2008 renovation of the Oliver T. Sherwood home. They are from accession number L2008.6.
  - Folder O
    - Letters from Elinor Thompson to her fiancé Chase Donaldson, ca. 1930; 10 items
  - Folder P
    - Letters to Chase Donaldson from unidentified, one may be from his mother Ethel Sprague, 1930; 2 items
    - Polo-Horse Show ticket, 1930
- Downs (Down) Family Papers, 1770-1861; Box I-Folder N; 21 items
  - Writ, Thomas Treadwell vs. Chauncey Downs, 1770
  - Writ, Joseph Smith vs. Nathaniel Down, 1773
  - Writ, Mary Downs vs. George Batterson, Jr., 1779
  - Deed from Elizabeth Sturges to Levi Down, 1840
  - Insurance papers to Levi Downs, 1845, 1849; 2 items
  - Estate papers of Levi Downs (1786-1855), 1843-1856
  - Estate papers of Mrs. Elizabeth Taylore Downs (1786-1861), 1857-1861; 9 items
- Dunning Family Papers, 1861-1887; Box I-Folder O; 4 items
  Elijah C. Dunning lived in Fairfield and then moved to Bridgeport around 1850.
  - Military papers of Elijah C. Dunning, 1861, 1867; 2 items
  - Builder's agreement between Julia A. Dunning and William Waterhouse, 20 Liberty St., Bridgeport, 1886
  - Room rentals to H.W. Morton, 20 Liberty St., 1887
- Eddy, George Papers, Box I-Folder P; 6 items
  George Eddy (1837-1916) lived on Osborn Place, Southport, CT.
  The items in this series were a gift of Emma Sundquist on 19 October 1977.
  - Account books--tax list with loose map, 1908-1915; 2 items
  - Account books--journals with loose papers, 1912-1916, n.d.; 4 items
- Eliot, Rev. Andrew Papers, 1779-1805; Box I-Folder Q; 7 items
  Rev. Andrew Eliot was born in Boston in 1744 and died in Fairfield in 1805. He was educated at Harvard and ordained the pastor of the First Church, Fairfield in 1774.
  - Sermon preached at First Church & Society, Fairfield, 1779
  - Sermon preached at Mr. S. Adams, 1792, 1794
  - Letters (copies) from A. Elliot, gift of A. Elizabeth Jennings, 1781; 2 items
  - Letter (copy) believed to be from Rev. Timothy Dwight, 1805
  - Original of above letter
  - Letter to Joseph Fish from A. Eliot, 1780
- Fairchild Family Papers, 1787-1855; Box I-Folder R; 8 items
  - Writ, Benjamin Fairchild vs. Abel Gold, 1787
  - Deed from Hiram Chapman to Samuel G. Fairchild, 1819
  - Deed from David L. Gray to Silliman A. Fairchild, 1839
  - Boat sale from Abraham Allen to Silliman Fairchild, 1852
  - Oyster planting permit to Silliman A. Fairchild (Westport), 1855; 2 items
  - Notice to Silliman Fairchild for rubbish removal, 1855
  - Promissory note to Silliman Fairchild, 1839
- Fitzgerald Family Papers, 1869-1881; Box I-Folder S; 54 items
  - Bill from Fairfield Middle School District (taxes) to Patrick Fitzgerald, 1873; 2 items
  - Bill from Town of Fairfield (taxes) to Patrick Fitzgerald, 1869-1875; 5 items
  - Misc. bills arranged by date, 1868-1881; 35 items
  - Misc. bills, n.d.; 12 items
- Forgue Family Papers, 1784-1791; Box I-Folder T; 11 items
  Sarah Dennie's (1724-1796) first husband was James Sayre and second husband Francis Forgue (1730-1783).
  - Administration of Dr. Francis Forgue's estate (photocopy from the CT State Library), 1784, 1791; 6 items
  - Deed from Ezra Wheeler to Sarah Forgue, 1783, 1784; 3 items
  - Deed from Sarah Forgue to James Hoyt, 1786; 2 items
- Frank, John M. Papers, Box V-Folder F
  - Account book of John M. Frank (Southport, CT), 1897-1899
- Gallagher, William D. Diary, 1880; Box VIII-Folder M
  William D. Gallagher (1845-1884) was the son of Dennis and Mary J. Banks Gallagher. William lived and worked on his father's farm and documented his activities in his diary. In addition to farming and visiting, he also kept a record of births, deaths, birthdays and anniversaries of friends and acquaintances.
- Gilbert, Burr papers, Box VIII-Folder C; 2 items
  - Appointment as Brigadier General, Connecticut militia, 1805
  - Bond, 1810 (Oversize Manuscript Box)